Inventory of the William John Fellner Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and writings, 1938-1983
  - "Gradualism Versus Prompt and Full Demand Disinflation with Shock Reducers," Group of Thirty paper, 1980-1981 (Box 4, 7, 24, 37, 50)
  - "Gold and the Uneasy Case for Responsibly Managed Fiat Money," Herbert Giersch Festschrift, 1980-1983 (Box 7, 26, 63)
  - "Introductory Remarks on Demand Disinflation: What if Gradualism Should Fail Despite Its Merits?" Contemporary Economic Problems, 1980 (Box 26, 45, 47)
  - "March into Socialism, or Viable Postwar Stage of Capitalism?" chapter in Schumpeter's Vision, correspondence and drafts, 1980-1981 (Box 13)
  - Paper for the Reagan/Bush Inflation Task Force Meeting headed by Paul McCracken, 1980 (Box 10)
  - "Policy Practices and Perry's Norm Shifts: The Horse and the Cart," Brookings Panel on Economic Activity, 1980 (Box 9)
  - "What if Gradualism Should Nevertheless Fail?" draft for Contemporary Economic Problems introduction, 1980 (Box 7)
  - "The Valid Core of Rational Expectations Theory and the Problem of Exchange-Rate Relations," paper for Triffin volume, 1980-1981 (Box 1, 4, 9, 13)
    - Conference version, correspondence, typescripts, and proofs, 1979-1980 (Box 48)
    - Typescripts, 1980 (Box 1, 4, 41, 46, 54-55, 67)
    - Typescripts and correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 13)
  - "An Appraisal of the State of Monetary Policy," paper for Conference Board, Colloquium on Alternatives for Economic Policy, 1981 (Box 12, 37, 54)
    Includes typescripts, correspondence, and colloquium summary
  - "The Austrians Revisited with a Timely Policy Problem in Mind", 1981 (Box 9)
  - "The Chances of Reasonably Soft Landing after a Period of Overheating", circa 1981 (Box 9)
  - "Comments on Professor Robert Triffin's Paper on the Threat to World Economic Order", 1981 (Box 10)
  - "Dealing With Inflationary Overtaxation: A Confusing Record", 1981 (Box 9-10)
  - "Discussion Paper on the Monetary Crisis" (CSIS Conference), circa 1981 (Box 10)
  - "Entrepreneurship in Economic Theory: The 'Scientific Method' and Vicarious Introspection," Jules Backman lecture, New York University, 1981-1983 (Box 7)
  - "A Further Look at the Question, What If Gradualism Should Fail Despite Its Merits?" Contemporary Economic Problems, draft, 1981 (Box 14, 55)
  - "Gold and the Uneasy Case for Responsibly Managed Fiat Money", 1981 (Box 1, 46, 54)
  - "The Hazy Distinction Between Voluntary and Involuntary Unemployment", circa 1981 (Box 10)
  - "In Defense of the Credibility Hypothesis", 1981 (Box 7)
  - "March Into Socialism or Viable Stage of Postwar Capitalism?", 1981 (Box 1)
  - "Monetary-Policy Problems of Interest to Those Whose Decisions Are Complementary with Fed Policy", circa 1981 (Box 9)
  - "On the Merits of Gradualism and on a Fall-back Position If It Should Nevertheless Fail," Contemporary Economic Problems, 1981 (Box 1, 48)
  - "Testimony Before the Finance Committee of the United States Senate", 1981 (Box 39, 51, 54)
  - "What If Gradualism as a Method of Disinflation Should Fail?", circa 1981 (Box 42)
  - "Why Policy Makers Need to Pay More Attention to the Crucial Role of Market Expectations," for the Joint Economic Committee, 1981 (Box 51)
  - "Approaches of Economists and of Other Observers to the Problems of Economic Growth", 1982 (Box 7)
  - "Aspects of the Problem of Budget Deficits," Contemporary Economic Problems, 1982 (Box 26)
  - "Comments on Professor Peacock's Paper: Some Suggested Modifications of Significant Conclusions", 1982 (Box 6, 19, 41)
  - "Criteria for Useful Targeting: Money Versus the Base and Other Variables,", 1982
    - Abstract, 1982 (Box 55)
    - Reprints, 1982 (Box 60)
    - Typescript and proofs, 1982 (Box 3, 6, 41, 54)
      Includes sketch of content
  - "Economic Policy for Recovery and Growth," with Phillip Cagan, Rudolph Penner, and Herbert Stein, 1982 (Box 5, 7)
  - "Economic Theory Amidst Political Currents: The Spreading Interest in Monetarism and in the Theory of Market Expectations", 1982
    - German version, "Wirtschaftstheorie im Kraftfeld gegenläufiger politischer Strömungen", 1982 (Box 6, 19, 62)
    - Proofs, 1982 (Box 6, 19)
  - "Entrepreneurship in Economic Theory", 1982 (Box 19)
  - "The High Employment Budget and the Potential Output: A Critique Focusing on Two Recent Contributions"
    - Comments, 1982 (Box 24)
    - Research and typescripts, 1982 (Box 68)
    - Printed copy, 1982 (Box 47)
    - Typescripts, 1982 (Box 6, 37, 48)
  - "Savings Flows" and "How Its Fits into the Scenario", 1982 February 19 (Box 1)
  - "The 1983 CEA Report: Back to Neo-Keynesianism?" (Box 49)
  - "The AEI Economist," paper on John Maynard Keynes, 1983 (Box 49)
  - "Comments on Monetary and Fiscal Policy", circa 1983 (Box 7-8)
  - "Comments and Suggestions Relating to Professor Boskin's Paper on Savings and Growth", circa 1983 (Box 7)
  - "Corporate Liquidity Under Stagflation and Disinflation", 1983 July 28 (Box 3)
  - "The Cost of Disinflation, Credibility and the Deceleration of Wages 1982-83," Fellner and Phillip Cagan, 1983 (Box 25, 32, 61-62)
  - "Currents and Countercurrents in Political and Economic Thought," Carnegie Rochester Conference Series on Public Policy 21, 1983 (Box 1, 25)
    See also Carnegie-Rochester conference file, box 26
  - "Monetary and Fiscal Policy in a Disinflationary Process: Justified and Unjustified Misgivings about Budget Deficits", 1983 (Box 37, 61, 67)
  - "Tentative Lessons from the Recent Disinflationary Effort," Phillip Cagan and Fellner, 1983 (Box 32)
  - "Testimony to Be Submitted to the Subcommittee on Domestic Monetary Policy of the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs, House of Representatives", 1983 (Box 14, 30)
- American Enterprise Institute file, 1975-1984
  Includes correspondence, conference materials, a transcript of a presentation by Friedrich August von Hayek, and materials related to the Cotemporary Economic Problems project.
  - Advisory Committee on Minimum Wage, 1978-1980 (Box 16)
  - Anti-inflation and credibility sessions, 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - Conference on Exchange Rate Flexibility, 1976 (Box 61)
  - Conference on International Comparisons of Productivity and Causes of the Slowdown, 1982 (Box 43)
  - Conference on Legal Minimum Wages, 1979 (Box 55)
    Includes Fellner's comments
  - Contemporary Economic Problems, 1979-1984
    - Chronological file
      Includes memoranda, correspondence, and typescripts of Fellner and other contributors, including Sven Arndt, Stanley Black, Phillip Cagan, Colin D. Campbell, Barry Chiswick, William Fellner, Murray Foss, Gottfried Haberler, D. Gale Johnson, John Kendrick, Marvin Kosters, Jack A. Meyer, Walter J. Mead, Geoffrey H. Moore, Attiat Ott, Mark Perlman, Thomas J Sargent, Herbert Stein, and John Weicher.
      - 1979 (Box 45)
      - 1980, contributor drafts (Box 46)
      - 1980, final copies of manuscripts (Box 45)
      - 1981 (Box 52, 63)
      - 1981, gold (Box 46)
      - 1981 to 1982, additional papers (Box 44)
      - 1982 (Box 49)
      - 1982 to 1983 (Box 52)
      - 1982 to 1983, figures and data (Box 44)
      - 1983 to 1984 (Box 39, 43, 51, 60-61)
        Includes report of progress by Fellner, project timetable, memoranda, and papers
    - Book reviews of Contemporary Economic Problems, 1976-1980 (Box 44)
    - Correspondence
      - 1979 (Box 48)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 47)
      - 1981 (Box 48)
      - 1982 (Box 48)
    - Correspondence, progress report, and The AEI Memorandum newsletter, 1982-1984 (Box 26)
    - Distribution and sales, 1982 (Box 44)
    - Economic policy project #2, 1976-1977 (Box 9)
    - Galley proofs of Contemporary Economic Problems, 1978 (Box 62)
    - Mailing list, 1979-1983 (Box 47)
    - Memoranda, 1978 (Box 19, 64)
    - Outlines for 1983 and 1984 projects (Box 48)
    - Papers by Fellner, 1977-1980 (Box 47-48)
    - Phillips Curve Project, 1983 (Box 37)
    - "The Present State of the Contemporary Economic Problems Project," by Fellner, undated (Box 5)
    - Summary and postscript by Gottfried Haberler, undated (Box 5)
    - Transcript of luncheon conference with Fellner, 1978 (Box 47)
    - Writing fragment, 1979 (Box 37)
  - "The Economic Planning Proposal", 1975 (Box 5)
  - Hayek, Friedrich August von, presentation transcript, 1975 (Box 60)
  - Japan-U.S. Assembly, 1975 (Box 59-60)
  - Monetary policy conference, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Press conference transcript, 1983 (Box 55)
  - Project on Major Economic Problems, 1975-1976 (Box 10-11, 37-38, 67)
  - Proposal by Phillip Cagan for a conference on monetary policy in a changing financial environment, 1983 (Box 25)
  - Proposal for a study group on international liquidity and lending policies by Thomas Willett, 1977 (Box 53)
  - Public Policy Week
    - 1980 (Box 20)
    - 1981 (Box 49)
    - 1982 (Box 5, 7)
  - Public Policy Forum on Inflation, transcripts, 1977 (Box 35)
  - Seminar on Rational Expectations, conference papers, 1980 (Box 54)
- Subject file, 1964-1983
  Includes correspondence, conference papers, and economic statistics related to various organizations and groups that Fellner was a part of, including the Council of Economic Advisors and the Gold Commission.
  - Allied Social Science Associations meeting, panel on international dimensions of monetary policy, 1977 (Box 35)
  - American Council for Capital Formation, "New Directions in Federal Tax Policy for the 1980s" conference, 1983 (Box 7)
  - Bellagio Group, Joint Conference of Officials and Academics, organized by the Bank of International Settlements, Basel, 1977 (Box 20)
    Includes letters from Fritz Machlup
  - British parliamentarians appointment with American Enterprise Institute staff, 1983 (Box 42)
  - Brookings Panel on Economic Activity
    - Agendas, correspondence, and proposals
      - 1975-1981 (Box 9, 15, 58)
      - 1983 (Box 55)
    - Agendas and conference papers
      - 1975-1977, 1981-1982 (Box 10, 32, 59)
      - 1983 (Box 62)
        Includes papers by Gary Burtless, John Campbell, Robert Lawrence, Bonnie Loopesko, James Medoff, Jeffrey Sachs, Kermit Schoenholz, Jeffrey Shafer, and Robert Shiller.
    - Conference papers
      See also Writings by others
      - 1976 (Box 20)
      - 1978 (Box 11)
      - 1979 (Box 30)
      - European Monetary System conference, 1979 (Box 11)
      - 1980 (Box 60)
      - 1982 (Box 38)
  - Bureau of Economic Analysis (BEA)
    - Memoradum from Zecher and Green to Alan Greenspan, 1975 (Box 5)
    - "Progress Report on Modifications to the Financial Sector of the BEA Econometric Model", undated (Box 5)
    - Quarterly Econometric Model Forecast, 1980 (Box 14)
  - Carnegie-Rochester conference, Florida, 1983 (Box 26)
  - Claremont McKenna College, "The Reagan Economic Policy" conference, 1982-1983 (Box 15, 49)
  - Conference Board, "Colloquium on Alternatives for Economic Policy," program and papers, 1981 (Box 43)
    Includes papers by Fellner, Gardner Ackley, Rudolph Penner, Theodore Schultz, and Herbert Stein
  - Congressional Budget Office
    Includes agendas, correspondence, memoranda, meeting materials, and reports.
    - 1975 (Box 30)
    - 1976 (Box 8, 61)
    - 1980 (Box 25, 44)
    - 1981 (Box 14, 39)
    - 1982 (Box 36, 50)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1983 (Box 35)
  - Council of Economic Advisors, Executive Office of the President
    - "The Current Status of the President's Program for Economic Recovery: A Background Paper for the Economic Policy Advisory Board", 1981 (Box 39)
    - "Economic Indicators", 1975 (Box 59)
    - Memoranda from George von Furstenberg, 1975 (Box 64)
    - Memoranda from David Munro, 1974-1975 (Box 38, 59)
    - Remarks by Fellner, 1974 (Box 5)
    - Reports, Herbert Stein,William Fellner, Marina van Neumann, and Gary Seevers, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
    - Statement by Herbert Stein, "Economic Developments in September", 1973 (Box 5)
  - Eurodollars and conferences in Switzerland, 1974-1975 (Box 18)
  - Fauntroy/House Finance Committee testimony, 1983 (Box 47)
  - Federal Reserve and other projects, 1980-1982 (Box 24)
  - Federal Reserve consultants meetings, 1978-1982 (Box 33, 50)
  - Federal Reserve, consumer price index (CPI), and GNP, 1983 (Box 43)
  - Federal Reserve statistics and publications, 1980 (Box 14)
  - Flow of funds, 1974-1975 (Box 8)
  - General economic research, notes, charts, and tables, 1969-1977, undated (Box 6, 8, 18, 38, 61)
  - Gold Commission
    - Letter from Thomas Leddy (Box 3)
    - Meeting transcripts, memoranda, and papers, 1981 (Box 18)
    - Memorandum and papers, 1980-1981 (Box 24)
    - Public hearings list of witnesses, 1981 November (Box 3)
    - Press release, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Report, "An Alternative Course", 1982 (Box 50)
    - Report to Congress, 1982 (Box 55)
    - Testimony of Fellner, "Views Presented to the Gold Commission", 1981 (Box 14, 51)
  - Gold statistics from 1976 to 1979 (Box 28)
  - Government grant for travel to Germany and Italy, 1970-1973 (Box 12)
  - Gramlich paper materials, 1976-1978 (Box 57)
  - Group of Thirty meeting, Charlottesville, VA, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Hermann Schumacher death notice, 1982 (Box 3)
  - International economic policy meeting, George Shultz, State Department, 1983 (Box 49)
  - International Monetary Advisory Board, 1981 (Box 17)
  - Indexation, 1974 (Box 39)
  - Inflation, 1974 (Box 39)
  - International indebtedness, 1983 (Box 60)
  - Kiel conferences, 1982 (Box 3, 6, 19, 37, 40)
  - Machlup, Fritz, memorial service, 1983 (Box 47)
  - Meeting of July 1977 (Box 35)
    Includes papers by Sherwin Rosen and Attiat Ott
  - Monetary file, 1973-1974 (Box 30)
  - Monetary policy, 1976-1982 (Box 19)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research, Conference on a Retrospective on the Classical Gold Standard, conference papers, 1981-1982 (Box 52, 68)
  - National Economists Club, board of directors meeting minutes, 1976 (Box 5)
  - New Troika, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Office of Management and Budget, Advisory Committee on the Balance of Payments, 1975 (Box 2, 30, 59)
  - Perloff-Wachter Study, 1978 (Box 53)
  - Perry material and project, undated (Box 37)
  - Perry unemployment rate with old residuals, data, undated (Box 39)
  - Productivity trends, charts, 1976-1977 (Box 8, 66)
    General note
    See also box 18
  - Project '87, papers of John Jay, 1980-1982 (Box 50)
    Project to promote study of the United States Constitution
  - Reagan and Bush campaign, 1980 (Box 26)
    Includes typescript of "Rough Draft of Statement on the International Monetary Problem" by Gottfried Haberler and Fellner
  - Statistical survey on oil data, 1975 (Box 59)
  - Task Force on International Monetary Policy, 1980 (Box 42)
  - Tax indexation (Box 22, 29)
  - Testimony of Fellner, 1975-1981 (Box 51, 54)
  - Treasury Consultants Meeting, "Economic Situation and Outlook", 1975 (Box 2, 59)
  - Yale University
    - Graduate course in economic theory (problems in the background of policy issues), 1972 (Box 12)
      - Correspondence, letters of recommendation, and list of participants, 1972-1973 (Box 13)
      - Syllabus, 1972 (Box 12)
    - Letter to Kingman Brewster, Jr., 1964 (Box 28)
- Writings by others, 1951-1984
  Includes conference papers, preliminary drafts, and published writings of economists. See also the correspondence file for papers enclosed with letters and the Contemporary Economic Problems file for papers submitted to that publication.
  - Adams, James, "Equalization of the True Gift and Estate Tax Rates," Conference on Tax Research, Treasury Department, 1975 (Box 3, 31)
  - Ashenfelter, Orley, "Evaluating the Effects of the Employment Tax Credit," prepared for Brookings Conference on November 30, 1977 (Box 59)
  - Baily, Martin Neil, "Contract Theory and the Moderation of Inflationary Expectations by Recession and by Controls", 1976 (Box 31)
  - Baquiast, Henri, "The European Monetary System and International Monetary Relations", undated (Box 11)
  - Barnett, William et al.
    - "The Information Content of Divisia Monetary Quantity Indices", 1980 (Box 55)
    - "New Concepts of Aggregated Money", undated (Box 54)
  - Barro, Robert J.
    - "Are Government Bonds Net Wealth?", 1974 (Box 8)
    - "Measuring the Average Annual Tax Rate from the Individual Income Tax," with Chaipat Sahaskul, 1982 (Box 50)
    - "Output Effects of Government Purchases", 1980 (Box 25)
    - "A Positive Theory of Monetary Policy in a Natural-Rate Model," with David B. Gordon, 1981 (Box 28)
    - "Public Debt and Taxes", 1978 (Box 67)
    - "Social Security and Private Saving", 1977 (Box 62)
  - Belassa, Bela
    - "The Income Distributional Parameter in Project Evaluation", 1975 (Box 59)
    - "Recent and Prospective Economic Developments in France", 1980 (Box 5)
  - Bennet, J.F., "The Outlook for the International Financial System After the Recent Oil Price Changes", 1983 (Box 62)
  - Bergsten et al., "Approaches to Greater Flexibility of Exchange Rates", 1970 (Box 5)
  - Bernstein, Edward M.
    - "The Economics of Fluctuating Exchange Rates", undated (Box 61)
    - "The Foreign Exchange Value of the Dollar and the U.S. Economy", 1983 (Box 50)
  - Bhatia, Kul, "International Bank for Reconstruction and Development", 1974 (Box 61)
  - Blinder, Alan S.
    - "The CPI and the (Mis)measurement of Recent Inflation," prepared for Brookings Panel on Economic Activity, 1980 (Box 60)
    - "Indexing the Economy through Financial Intermediation," preliminary draft, 1975 (Box 30)
  - Boskin and Green, "Taxation and Capital Formation: Missing Elements in the President's Tax Program", 1978 February (Box 1)
  - Bourguinat, Henri, "The New French Financial and Monetary Policy", 1980 (Box 66)
  - Boyes and Kaufman, "Credibility Hypothesis: A Theoretical and Empirical Analysis", 1984 October (Box 1)
  - Bradford, David F., "Cutting and Reforming the Personal Income Tax", 1978 February (Box 1)
  - Brainard, William, John Shoven, and Lawrence Weiss, "The Financial Valuation of the Return to Capital", 1980 (Box 60)
  - Brennan and Buchanan, "Toward a Tax Constitution for Leviathan", 1977 (Box 3)
  - Brittan, Samuel
    - "How English Is the English Sickness?" Eighth Henry Simons Lecture, 1978 (Box 67)
    - "Washington Sounds a New Note", 1982 (Box 3, 6)
  - Broida, Arthur L., draft for Inflation Watch, 1982 (Box 41)
  - Browning, Edgar, "Welfare Reform", undate (Box 36)
  - Brozen, Yale, "The Road to Recovery", 1976 (Box 36)
  - Bryant, Ralph C., "Financial Interdependence and Variability in Exchange Rates," prepared for colloquium Europe and the Dollar in the World Disequilibrium, 1979 (Box 30)
  - Buiter, Willem and Marcus Miller, "The Economic Consequences of Mrs. Thatcher", 1983 (Box 50)
  - Burns, Arthur, "Regaining a Stable Price Level", 1981 (Box 54)
  - Butschak, Felix, "Full Employment During Recession," prepared for AEI conference on Political Economy of Austria, 1981 (Box 30)
  - Buttler, Hans-Jurg and Kurt Schiltknecht, "Transitory Changes in Monetary Policy and Their Implications on Money Stock Control", 1982 (Box 42)
    See also correspondence, S file, box 33
  - Cagan, Phillip
    - "The Choice Among Monetary Aggregates as Targets and Indicators for Monetary Policy," AEI conference, 1982 (Box 14)
    - "The Effect of Government Deficits on Aggregate Demand and Financial Markets: A Wide-ranging Review of the Literature and Current Policy Issues" (Box 41)
    - "Monetary Policy, undated (Box 8)
    - "Monetary Policy and Inflation Since 1973", 1976 (Box 57)
    - "Monetary Problems and Policy Choices in Reducing Inflation and Unemployment", 1976 (Box 38)
    - "Public Policy Week", undated (Box 5)
    - "The Reduction of Inflation by Slack Demand", 1978 (Box 34)
  - Chase Econometric Associates, "The Economic Impact of NASA R&D Spending Appendices", 1975 (Box 56, 62)
  - Chiswick, Barry
    - "The Effect of Americanization on Earnings", 1976 (Box 31)
    - "Immigrants and Immigration Policy", 1978 (Box 34)
  - Clark, Kim and Lawrence Summers, "Labor Market Dynamics and Unemployment: A Reconsideration," prepared for Brookings Panel on Economic Activity, 1979 (Box 58)
  - Clark, Lindley, "How We Got Into the Monetarist Mess", 1983 (Box 6)
  - Coats, Warren L., Jr.
    - "Can the Federal Reserve Control the Money Supply?", undated (Box 52)
    - "Recent Monetary Policy Strategies in the United States", 1980 (Box 4)
  - Cooper, Richard, "The Gold Standard: Historical Facts and Future Prospects," prepared for the Brookings Panel on Economic Activity, 1982 (Box 38)
  - Corden, W. M., "The Effect of the Oil Price Rise on the International Economy: Theoretical Framework", 1975 (Box 58)
  - Cox, James and Arthur Wright, "Taxation, Public Policy and the Petroleum Industry," Conference on Tax Policy, Treasury Department, 1975 (Box 31)
  - Crandall, Robert W., "Federal Government Initiatives to Reduce the Price Level," prepared for the Brookings Panel on Economic Activity, 1978 (Box 61, 64)
  - Denison, Edward F., "Discussion", 1978 (Box 34)
  - Department of the Treasury, "Government Deficit Spending and Its Effects on Prices of Financial Assets", 1983 (Box 62)
  - Dernburg, Thomas, "Inflation Indexing of the Personal income Tax," International Monetary Fund, 1975 (Box 59)
  - Dildine, Larry and Emil Sunley, "The Administrative Problems of Tax-Based Incomes Policies," prepared for Brookings Panel on Economic Activity, 1978 (Box 60)
  - Diller, Stanley, "Credit Allocation", 1976 (Box 5)
  - Dornbusch, Rudiger
    - Chapter on economic policy with Stan Fischer, undated (Box 36)
    - "Exchange Rates and the Capital Mobility Problem" (Box 9)
    - "Lecture Notes on Macroeconomics: Part V, Inflation and Unemployment", 1975 (Box 64)
  - Dreyer, Jacob
    - "Free World Industrial Demand for Gold", 1980 (Box 41)
    - Memorandum on direct cost of maintaining an official price of gold, 1980 (Box 41)
    - "Returns on Gold and Alternative Financial Assets", 1980 (Box 41)
  - Dunning, John, "Economic Analysis and the Multinational Enterprise", 1972 (Box 5)
  - Eisner, Robert and Paul J. Pieper, "A New View of the Federal Debt and Budget Deficits", 1983 (Box 30)
  - Ellis, Howard S., "Some Notes Toward a Successful Analysis of Stagflation", undated (Box 34)
  - Emerson, Michael, "The European Monetary System in the Broader Setting of the Community's Economic and Political Development", 1979 (Box 11)
  - Emminger, Otmar, "On the Way to a New International Monetary Order", 1976 (Box 58)
  - Englander, Steve and Cornelis Los, "The Stability of the Phillips Curve and Its Implications for the 1980s", 1983 (Box 39)
  - Erb, Richard
    - "Oil and Metals Don't Mix", undated (Box 38)
    - "The OPEC Financial Surpluses and the International Financial System", 1980 (Box 42)
  - Federal Reserve press releases and papers, 1976-1977, 1980 (Box 2, 5)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 2)
    - 1980 (Box 5)
    - "Analysis of the Impact of Lagged Reserve Accounting", 1977 (Box 39)
  - Feige, Edgar L., "A New Perspective on Macroeconomic Phenomena", 1980 (Box 42, 54)
  - Feldstein, Martin
    - "Inflation, Income Taxes and the Rate of Interest: A Theoretical Analysis," Conference on Tax Research, Treasury Department, 1975 (Box 3, 31, 60)
    - "Inflation, Tax Rules, and the Long Term Interest Rate," with Lawrence Summers, 1977 (Box 10)
    - "Is the Rate of Profit Falling?" with Lawrence Summers, 1977 (Box 5)
    - "The Stagflation Problems," testimony before the Joint Economic Committee, 1979 (Box 58)
    - "Strengthening Social Security," testimony before Ways and Means Committee, 1975 (Box 59)
    - "Temporary Layoffs in the Theory of Unemployment", 1975 (Box 64)
  - Fischer, Stanley, "Wage-Indexation and Macroeconomic Stability", 1975 (Box 30)
  - Flanagan, Robert J., "Wage Interdependence in Unionized Labor Markets", 1976 (Box 31)
  - Fort, Donald, "Curbing Inflation Without Recession", 1980 (Box 54)